STEPHANIE E. AYUBA

stephanieesha@gmail.com | + 2348063399186 | https://www.linkedin.com/in/stephanie-ayuba-5121271a8

SUMMARY

QA Engineer with 5+ years experience and a specialization in automation with Cypress and Selenium. Passionate about finding bugs and releasing quality software. Implemented regression testing processes that achieved a 50 % reduction in bugs found in production within 9 months of hire. Dedicated to improving testing processes to enhance team collaboration and align testing practices with company goals. Always excited to learn new things, currently learning Robot Framework for better User Acceptance testing.

EDUCATION

Federal University of Technology, Minna BEng in Computer Engineering & Varsity Volleyball Niger State, Nigeria

CERTIFICATIONS

International Software Testing Qualifications Board ISTQB certified Foundation Level Tester

SKILLS

Technical Skills

- Languages Python, ReactJs, JavaScript, Typescript, HTML5, CSS, SQL.
- Automation Frameworks/Libraries Selenium, Appium, XCUITest, Playwright, Cypress, Cucumber, Testim, JMeter.
- Cloud Platforms Development and Management with AWS, MongoDB and Firebase.
- CI/CD pipeline implementation with Jenkins, Kubernetes & Docker.
- Linux server setup, configuration, and maintenance.
- Git and GitHub Commands.
- API testing REST and SOAP.
- AI testing frameworks SmartBear and Testim.
- Test Case Development and Maintenance.
- Agile Software Development and Testing Methodologies, and Software Development Life Cycle(SDLC).
- Test Reporting and Management with Zephyr, Excel.
- Project Management and CRM with Trello, JIRA, Slack, Hubspot, Aha!
- System Log Analysis with SumoLogic and New Relic.

Soft skills

Globo

- Good People Management Skills
- **Detail Oriented**
- Strong Problem-Solving and Analytical Skills
- Team Player
- Good Communication and Collaboration skills
- Good Written and Spoken English

WORK EXPERIENCE

Philadelphia PA, USA

March 2022 – Present Software Quality Assurance Engineer Work closely with the team to increase automation test coverage and focus manual testing efforts on new features. Write

and maintain manual test cases and follow industry trends to improve testing processes. Automation testing

- Writing automation tests with Cypress to achieve over 60% automation test coverage on company products.
- Writing automation tests for mobile apps Android with Appium in Python and Testim for iOS.
- Implementing and Managing CI/CD pipelines for test automation projects.
- Spearheading the AI testing initiative with SmartBear and Testim to generate and maintain manual test cases, and create automation test scripts with computer vision.

Test Execution

- Writing and executing API test scripts with Postman to verify user permissions and validate responses.
- Performing User Acceptance testing to ensure the system is easy to use by the target audience and meets the necessary ISO/IEC standards.
- Performing End to End and Regression testing on web and mobile platforms before each sprint release by running automation tests and performing manual functional tests.

Bug triaging and defect management

- Finding bugs and defects in software, reproducing and tracking issues to JIRA.
- Testing to verify bug fixes, documenting results and closing issues.
- Frequent Exploratory testing with different user scenarios to find bugs and defects, thus reducing the overall number of bugs found in production by 50 %.

Leadership & Testing Best Practices

- Collaborating with the development team to reproduce and resolve bugs and issues.
- Adequate Documentation of testing procedures to ensure traceability and easy onboarding for new teammates.
- Championed the shift left approach in the engineering team and aligned testing practices with Agile Development which resulted in fewer bugs found at the end of a sprint.

Test case development and management

- Analyzing user stories and requirements, and applying critical thinking to create test cases.
- Updating and maintaining test cases in accordance with feature updates.

Data Analysis and validation

• Executing ETL testing to improve the billing and payment process for clients and interpreters, resulting in a 70% reduction in the manual payment process.

Core Technologies Used: Zephyr, JIRA, SmartBear, Cypress, Appium, Testim, Postman, SQL.

Ehealth4everyone Abuja, Nigeria

Software Quality Assurance Tester and Manager

July 2019 – February 2021

As QA manager, worked closely with Engineering Lead to ensure application met business requirements and testing standards were maintained. As QA tester, performed functional and non functional tests to find bugs and defects in software.

Automation testing

- Automation testing with Selenium in Python to achieve 50% automation test coverage on company web apps.
- Automation for mobile testing with Appium in Python and XCUITest to replicate user flows and reduce time spent on regression testing.

Leadership & Testing Best Practices

- Successfully led and mentored 5 team members ranging from entry level to mid level on the QA team, enhancing their skills and performance through 1: 1 reviews and peer working sessions.
- Curated testing practices such as shift left testing and frequent team retrospectives that aligned testing processes with Agile software development.
- Spearheaded team retrospectives/Post-Project Meetings at the end of every sprint release to identify and maintain successes, sought process improvements, and planned future enhancements, thus boosting team collaboration.

Test Execution

- Executed Speed and Performance tests with WebPageTest and Blazemeter on the company website that led to the reduction of page load time by 40%.
- Provided clear and concise test reports to stakeholders and development team, and proffered solutions to minimize risks of failures on business.
- Executed stress and load tests with JMeter to monitor the system's behavior at different loads, identify the system's capacity for scalability, and to ensure it functioned as expected within its threshold.
- Carried out User Acceptance testing on newly developed health tech software to validate business requirements and ensure the system was easy to use by the target audience.
- Performed functional tests on health data and triangulation dashboards used by The Federal Ministry of Health (FMOH) Nigeria.

Bug triaging and reporting

• Carried out frequent Exploratory testing to source for bugs and minimize potential failures in production environment, resulting in a 20% reduction in customer related bug reports.

Test case development and management

• Analyzed user stories and product requirements to create test cases for features.

Core Technologies Used: JMeter, JIRA, Selenium, Appium, XCUITest, WebPageTest, Blazemeter, Aha!, Trello.

LEADERSHIP

SheCodeAfrica

Javascript & QA Career Mentor

July 2020 - Present

- Successfully led 5 women in the Javascript Cohort 4 mentorship program from April June 2023, in basic and advanced javascript, supervised weekly tasks and final program projects, and improved soft skills.
- Actively Engage in monthly 1: 1 mentoring sessions with 3 QA Engineers, providing guidance and feedback on the QA industry.
- Collaborating with fellow mentees and mentors to share insights, experiences and, and knowledge to foster a positive learning community.

ADDITIONAL PROJECTS

Shirley Finance App https://shirly.onrender.com - An Expense tracking app I built with MERN stack to track monthly expenses, generate curated shopping lists based on history and preferences, and display expenses in charts for easy comparison over certain periods. Currently used by over 10 family and friends.

Esha's Memory Game https://stephanies-brain-teaser.netlify.app. A fun card game I built with Javascript that tests a player's attention to details and memory. Players pay attention to the cards as they shuffle and match identical cards when they flip.